# Kevin L. Miller, Ph.D.

klmille@gmail.com | (310) 562-4572 | Los Angeles, CA 90230 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-miller-phd-1b197986 Web Design Portfolio: https://kevin-miller-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Chemist with a breadth of learning. Experienced independent researcher, business manager, scientist, and problem solver. Values include community, ethics, integrity, and business sense. Leadership, teamwork, and public speaking skills stem from years spent as a classroom teacher and a group fitness leader. Top aim is to find success in life and improve the lives of others.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Knowledge of the importance of lab safety gained through years of chemical laboratory experience
- Skill with swiftly diving into both scientific research and industrial chemical production
- Practical experience with lab work, scientific literature surveys, chemistry teaching, procedure writing, scientific writing, and process development
- Extensive practical experience and background knowledge of common lab techniques such as NMR and IR/UV-Vis spectroscopy, cyclic voltammetry, Schlenk and glovebox work, HPLC, mass spectrometry, titration, pH and conductivity testing, synthesis, crystallization, distillation, purification
- Specialized chemistry knowledge of inorganic chemistry and immunohistochemistry
- Basic general pathology and statistics knowledge
- Coding experience includes languages such as JavaScript/HTML/CSS, Python, C/C++, SQL, as well as techniques such as object-oriented programming, API interaction, and Git version control

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

## **Agilent Technologies**

August 2021 - Current

Biochemical Production Manufacturing Chemist

- Quickly learned chemical processes in order to become an organized and valuable team member
- Consistently willing to go above and beyond to study immunohistochemistry and find best practices
- Leads biochemical production department as the continuous improvement champion, which has resulted in multiple time-saving changes that have reduced waste and saved employee time
- Collaborates with the process development department in gathering data, contributing to studies, and performing statistical analysis
- Utilizes SAP enterprise resource planning system and Agile Oracle database for daily tasks as well as investigation of logistics issues

#### Twinwood, Inc.:

Property Manager and Accountant

October 2013 - July 2021

- Managed over a dozen buildings while responsible for business decisions on properties worth millions
- Meticulous business analytics helped achieve a yearly company growth rate of 3.6% of net worth
- Improved value of multiple properties, saving thousands of dollars on outside contractor hires
- Rigorous documentation of construction projects and account tracking benefitted bottom line

#### **Independent Chemistry Tutor:**

 Praised for making a "night and day" difference by helping high school students learn chemistry, improve grades, and appreciate science

## Aim-Hi Global, LLC. | https://aimhiglobal.com

December 2020 - April 2021

Web Development Intern

• Implemented user settings, added routing functionality, refactored code, designed interactive calendar, used social media APIs, deployed website, and improved documentation

#### Praxair:

Lab Technician and Analytical Scientist

October 2014 - February 2015

• Carefully managed lab testing allowed for a fast throughput of dozens of highly pure gasses daily

#### University of California, Los Angeles:

Researcher / Teaching Assistant

Sept. 2007 - December 2014

- Intense scientific research led to seven published research papers
- Personal mentoring of two undergraduates helped them publish their own scientific papers
- Chemistry research was awarded Ralph and Charlene Bauer Award and two separate fellowships
- Close supervision of hundreds of students in over a dozen college labs and discussion sections

## Chromadex, Inc.:

June 2006 - June 2007

Associate inventory manager

• Handled chemical inventory and improved organization for botanical reference standards company

## **EDUCATION**

CS50 Computer Science Professional Certificate - HarvardX Online

Full-Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp - UCLA Extension

Completed 2020

Ph.D., Chemistry - University of California, Los Angeles

September 2007 - December 2014

**B.S., Chemistry -** University of California, Irvine

September 2003 - July 2007

## **PUBLICATIONS**

Reactions of group III biheterocyclic complexes. Carver, C. T.; Benitez, D.; Miller, K. L.; Williams, B. N.; Tkatchouk, E.; Goddard, W. A.; Diaconescu, P. L.; *J. Am. Chem. Soc.* **2009**, *131*, 10269-10278.

Dearomatization reactions of N-heterocycles mediated by group III complexes. Miller, K. L.; Williams, B. N.; Benitez, D.; Carver, C. T.; Ogilby, K. R.; Tkatchouk, E.; Goddard III, W. A.; Diaconescu, P. L.; J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2010, 132, 342-355.

Reactions of aromatic N-heterocycles with a lutetium benzyl complex supported by a ferrocene-diamide ligand. Wong, A. W.; Miller, K. L.; Diaconescu, P. L.; Dalton Trans. 2010, 39, 6726-6731.

Reactions of imidazoles with electrophilic metal alkyl complexes. Miller, K. L.; Williams, B. N.; Carver, C. T.; Diaconescu, P. L.; Organometallics 2010, 29, 2272-2281.

Group 3 metal complexes of radical-anionic 2,2'-bipyridyl ligands. Williams, B. N.; Huang, W.; Miller, K. L.; Diaconescu, P. L.; *Inorg. Chem.* 2010, 49, 11493-11498.

An unusual hydrogen migration/C-H activation reaction with group 3 metals. Williams, B. N.; Benitez, D.; Miller, K. L.; Tkatchouk, E.; Goddard, W. A.; Diaconescu, P. L.; *J. Am. Chem. Soc.* **2011**, *133*, 4680-4683.

Synthesis of symmetrically and unsymmetrically 3,5-dimethylbenzyl-substituted 1,1'-ferrocene diamines. Lee, J. A.; Williams, B. N.; Ogilby, K. R.; Miller, K. L.; Diaconescu, P. L.; J. Organomet. Chem. 2011, 696, 4090-4094.

Unique Properties and Reactivity of Electrophilic Metal Centers Supported by Ferrocene Diamide Ligands. Miller, K. L.; *UCLA* 2014.